Contact

arun.das@my.utsa.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/arun-das (LinkedIn) github.com/arundasan91 (Other)

Top Skills

Cloud Computing
Machine Learning
Deep Learning

Languages

Malayalam (Full Professional)
Hindi (Full Professional)
English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Neural Networks and Deep Learning Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization

Convolutional Neural Networks

Biomedical Research, Stage 1 - Basic Course

Honors-Awards

Alvarez Master's Research Competitive Scholarship

NSF Cloud Stipend

UTSA Brain Health Consortium (BHC) Seed Grant

Publications

DeceptionNet: Al Model for Encoding Deception using Facial Micro-Expression

Patient Facial Emotion Recognition and Sentiment Analysis Using Secure Cloud With Hardware Acceleration

Image Graph Production by Dense Captioning

Arun Das

Al Enthusiast, PhD Candidate at UT San Antonio.

Summary

"Intelligence and knowledge are great assets, so is an open mind to learn."

I graduated with Masters in Computer Engineering from The University of Texas at San Antonio (UTSA) in the Fall of 2016, worked an year as a full-time Research Fellow, and is currently pursuing a PhD in Electrical Engineering with concentration in Artificial Intelligence at UTSA. I am intrigued with deep learning and edge computing, so keeping myself abreast of the technologies every single day. My current research focus is in computer vision algorithms for healthcare and robotics - with an emphasis on real-world implementations. If you would like to talk more about my research, feel free to contact me at arundas.utsa [at] gmail.com (alternate email).

Find me on Github: https://github.com/arundasan91, https://arundasan91.github.io/

Experience

The Open Cloud Institute Research Fellow September 2015 - Present (5 years)

San Antonio, Texas Area

- Invented a system and methods for evaluating group emotion engagement and attention from images and videos.
- Licensed the intellectual property to a start-up based on Austin, Texas and mentored them through the process.
- Developed and implemented a scalable machine learning and AI software stack on top of OpenStack.
- Mentored 3 graduate students towards their thesis and published research papers.

Distributed Machine Learning
Cloud TeleOphthalmology IoT for
Predicting AMD Disease Progression

A Distributed Secure Machine-Learning Cloud Architecture for Semantic Analysis

Patents

Systems and methods for evaluating individual, group, and crowd emotion engagement and attention

- Taught and coordinated the Machine Learning Club of Secure Al and Autonomy Laboratory at OCI.
- Motivates colleagues and students to write better code, build better teams and improve quality of research.
- Go to guy for Linux environment setup and queries, python code debugging and hyper-parameter tuning of neural networks.

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/arundasan91

Intel Corporation
Al Graduate Intern
May 2019 - August 2019 (4 months)

Greater San Diego Area

I worked with Intel Artificial Intelligence Product Group (AIPG) Research Lab as an AI Graduate Intern during the Summer of 2019 on LSTM enablement for Intel accelerator chips. I implemented recurrent neural network architectures, listed required ops to be enabled, and had biweekly discussions with the whole team on LSTM ops and requirements. I thoroughly studied and presented Google's NMT, Transformers, BERT, etc. and looked at ways to support ops requirements. All code and presentations developed were handed over to my wonderful data science team.

The Open Cloud Institute and Intel Corporation OpenStack Developer Intern September 2016 - December 2016 (4 months) San Antonio, Texas Area

- Acquired expertise in various OpenStack services and researched on Machine Learning system design for the cloud.
- Developed deep-learning ready cloud appliances for one-click deployment on accelerated GPU and CPU clouds.
- Gained knowledge in various service API's driving the backend python scripts.
- Learned about network isolation, namespaces, encapsulation, bridges and iptable rules.
- Learned about token issuing, endpoints, swift architecture and volumes.

Education

The University of Texas at San Antonio

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Electrical Engineering, Artificial

Intelligence · (2018 - 2021)

The University of Texas at San Antonio

Master of Science (M.S.), Computer Engineering · (2015 - 2016)

Cochin University of Science and Technology
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Electrical and Electronics
Engineering · (2009 - 2013)